librarika.com 2019-06-03

# Librarika: Privacy Policy

Last modified: May 24, 2018

### 1\. Introduction

**Librarika** , a service of **Raynux** , values the privacy and security of the information that you share with us. This Privacy Statement applies to the information collected by librarika, registered librarika libraries and related services. This Privacy Statement also apply to other information Librarika receives from Europe though other means such as customer quries, support emails, community posting etc. This Statement describes how Librarika collects, uses, shares, protects, or otherwise processes your personal information. 

**By using this website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement.**

### 2\. Collection and Use of Information

Librarika collects personal information to set up and manage accounts for our library services and to handle loans of library materials and related services from Librarika. 

You may need to provide Librarika with personal information such as:

  * names; phone numbers; mailing, billing, shipping, and email addresses; password; bio; profile picture; social network user identifier;

Librarika uses such information for:

  * website registration; enabling joining of library services, write reviews
  * providing customer service; important service notification and reminders;
  * marketing and surveys; sending service update notices;
  * measuring, improving, and customizing our services; and
  * fulfilling other technical, logistical, financial, tax, legal, compliance, administrative, or back office functions.

####  Member or Patron Information 

Librarika collects information on each patrons of its registered libraries. This information is usually submitted by library officials through their library dashboard or when a user join a library in the platform. Such information may include patron name; patron no; patron mailing and email addresses; patron picture; patron phone; 

Librarika uses such information for enabling librarians to handle their daily library activities such as check-in/check-out of library materials, generate barcodes, generate loan receipts, identify books borrowed by patrons, etc. These informations are purely stored for the specific library and only used for that dedicate purpose. Librarika carefully separates partons personal info with the system users personal info to ensure better data security. 

#### Community Information

Librarika collects information from you to post or review entries to our discover section, community website, forums or issues site. Such information may include your email address, Internet Protocol address, user name, date and time of signup, and date and time of posts/reviews to the forum. 

Librarika uses this information for the secure and efficient functioning of our website, to provide you with access to our community site, to detect and prevent violations of our legal agreements, and as part of any legal obligations related to our community website. 

####  Transaction Information 

Librarika collects information on each transaction processed through its third party payment processor. Such information may include the amount of the transaction; the plan subscribed; the identity of the customer; the sale and order number; the transaction and recurring date, payment type; currency; location; Internet Protocol address; and websites visited. Librarika does store any bank account or credit card information in its database. 

Librarika uses such information for refunds, for customer service, for website optimization, or for other administrative or business purposes. Librarika may share information related to the transactions you conduct through our website with your co-library admins of your library for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Statement. Librarika retains transaction information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations. 

#### Customer Service Correspondence

Librarika also collects information involving customer service correspondence. This information may include emails, internet chats, faxes, or telephone calls directed to our customer service centers. Librarika processes this information to provide customer service, handle complaints or disputes, measure and improve our customer service, detect and prevent fraud, and detect and prevent violations of our legal agreements. Librarika retains customer service information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations. 

#### Cookies and Logs

Librarika collects information related to your use of our website using cookies and log information.

Cookies are small files containing strings of text stored on your computer. Librarika uses cookies to authenticate you as a user when you log in, track your session to keep it active, deliver content specific to your preferences and interests, and provide other functions. 

Log information may include web requests, Internet Protocol address, operating system, browser type, browser language, date and time of your request, and cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. Librarika uses this information to enhance the functionality of the website and to make your access more convenient, secure, and efficient. 

Librarika also uses information gathered from logs and cookies to monitor website performance; improve website design, functionality, and security; and assemble web analytics and activity trends. Librarika retains such information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations. 

You may stop your browser from accepting cookies. The Help portion of your browser should explain how to configure your browser’s cookie handling. You may have limited functionality if you block cookies set by our website. 

#### Amazon Ads

Librarika uses Amazon Ads, to show you ads in limited scale that we think may interest you. Amazon Ads may use cookies, web beacons, and other means to help Librarika analyze how users use the site. You may find Amazon Ads’s Privacy Statement and GDPR policy at <https://advertising.amazon.com/ad-specs/en>. 

#### Google Analytics

Librarika uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. Google Analytics uses cookies, web beacons, and other means to help Librarika analyze how users use the site. You may find Google’s Privacy Policy at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>. 

#### 2Checkout

Librarika uses 2Checkout.com also knows as "2Checkout" or "2CO", a payment processor to process subscription payments on its behalf. 2Checkout may use cookies, logs, web beacons or other means to identify and validate your transactions. You may find 2Checkout’s privacy statement at <https://www.2checkout.com/policies/privacy-policy>. 

#### Facebook Login

Librarika uses Facebook Login to log you into the website smoothly. This login method is an additional alternative to our regular login mechanism which you can enable / disable any time. Facebook may use cookies, logs, web beacons or other means to provide the login service. You may find Facebook’s privacy statement at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>. 

###  3\. Choice 

We will seek your consent prior to using your personal information in a manner incompatible with the purposes we described in our Privacy Statement at the time of collection. You may choose not to provide any personal information to Librarika, in which case we will be unable to provide services to you. 

### 4\. Sharing of Information

Librarika only shares information as described in this Privacy Statement. Librarika shares information with the following categories of third parties. Such third parties are prohibited by law or by contract from processing personal information for purposes other than those disclosed in this Privacy Statement. 

#### Organizations that Provide Services to Us

Librarika discloses personal information to other organizations that perform services on our behalf. We require such organizations to use such information solely for the purposes of providing services to us and to protect the personal information with appropriate safeguards. 

Such organizations include cloud service providers; payment processors; acquirers; auditors; database managers; customer service providers and representatives; and others who perform technical, logistical, financial, tax, legal, compliance, or administrative functions on our behalf. 

These organizations may perform functions such as cloud infrastructure managing, processing credit and debit card payments, providing customer service, processing data, sending postal mail and email, and providing other financial, technical, logistical, tax, legal, compliance, or administrative functions. 

#### Librarians

Librarika discloses personal information to its librarians. Librarika provides library management services to its registered libraries enabling library materials and services available to their patrons for reading or accessing through their librarika library website. You join willingly by either accepting the email invitation or submitting member access requests. During this time your name, email address, profile picture, etc is shared with the joining library. We share personal information with respective library officials to complete thier library activities, resolve customer comments or complaints, and for administrative and analytical purposes like accounting, billing and audits, information system management, and other uses. 

#### Patrons

Librarika discloses personal information to its patrons. Librarika provides library management services to librarians who make library materials and services available to their patrons for reading or accessing through their librarika library website. We may share personal information with patrons to complete activities, resolve customer comments or complaints, and for administrative purposes like accounting, billing and audits, and other uses. 

#### Business Sale or Merger

Librarika may share personal information in the event of a sale or merger of all or any portion of its business units. Such information remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Statement, unless an individual consents otherwise. 

#### Other

Librarika may disclose personal information where: 

  * required by law or by an order or requirement of a court, administrative agency, or other government entity, or by court rules concerning the production of records;
  * Librarika has reasonable grounds to believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect the rights, privacy, property, or safety of our users or others;
  * Librarika has reasonable grounds to believe that the information relates to the breach of an agreement or violation of the law that has been, is being, or is about to be committed;
  * it is necessary for fraud protection, risk reduction, or the establishment or collection of funds owed to us;
  * it is necessary to enforce or apply our legal agreements, to pursue remedies, or to limit damages to Librarika;
  * the information is public;
  * you have provided consent or with your direction; or
  * other reasons allow it or other laws require it.

When we are required or permitted to disclose information, we will not disclose more information than is necessary to fulfill the disclosure purpose. 

Librarika may disclose aggregate or statistical information to our business partners, for public relations purposes, or other purposes.

### 5\. Access

At your request, we will provide you with reasonable access to your personal information, so that you can review what we have stored and, if you choose, request corrections to it. You may request access by writing to us at the address listed in the Contact Information section below. After you request access, we will provide the personal information that you request as soon as practically possible and generally no later than thirty days following the request. If you wish to correct your personal information, please send us a written explanation of the particular information that you believe should be corrected. Where information will not or cannot be accessed or amended, we will tell you the reasons. 

Librarika stores, collects, and otherwise processes information mainly in Amsterdam, Netherlands. We mostly access the data from our end computers located in Bangladesh.

If you are residing in the European Union/ the European Economic Area, you have the right to:

  * access your personal information, rectify it, restrict or object to its processing, or request its deletion,
  * to receive the personal information you provided to Librarika or to transmit it to another company. More specifically, based on the European Union laws, you may request and receive copies of the personal information that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider (where technically feasible).
  * to withdraw any consent provided,
  * to opt out of some collection or uses of your personal information, including the use of cookies and similar technologies, the use of your personal information for marketing purposes, and the use for data analyses,
  * where applicable, to lodge a complaint with your supervisory authority.

We encourage to contact us and we will respond in due time to settle all your questions and requests to the extent permitted by law.

### 6\. Security

Librarika combines technical and physical safeguards with employee policies and procedures to protect your information. We work to protect your personal information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer software, which encrypts the information that you provide online at our website. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to protect your information. We will also continue to assess new technology for protecting information and upgrade our information security systems when appropriate. 

Further, we permit only authorized Librarika employees and third parties to access any personal information. If an employee misuses personal information, we may take disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment. If any third party individual or organization misuses personal information, we will take action, up to and including termination of any agreement between Librarika and that individual or organization. 

### 7\. Data Integrity

Librarika processes personal information only for the purposes it was originally collected and in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Librarika takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure that the personal data is relevant, reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current for the purposes for which it is used. Librarika retains information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations. 

### 8\. Children

Librarika does not offer account login services to children, any library activities or communications for childrens should be facilitied by adults on their behalf (teachers or parents or leagal gurdians). We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under age 13 to be used for account logins or other purposes unless otherwise stated in this statement. If you are under age 13, do not share personal information with us. 

In the European Union, the age limitation is 16. Thus, if this jurisdiction applies to you, Librarika will not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under age 16. 

For school libraries, where students / childrens are the main library users, library administrators (as data controller under EU GDPR law) will be fully liable to ensure necessary legal consent (parental, legal gurdians) and may enter students / childrens data into the system for library management purpose only. 

### 9\. Links to Other Websites

When you click on a link on this website that takes you to a website operated by another company, you will be subject to that company’s privacy practices. 

### 10\. Controlling Unsolicited Email

We may send you information about our products and services. You may log into the settings section and update your Preferences to stop receiving this information. You may also opt out of Librarika’s marketing list or update your information by notifying us at [info@raynux.com](mailto:info@raynux.com) at any time. 

### 11\. Amendments

Librarika may amend this Privacy Statement on one or more occasions by posting a revised statement on this website or a similar website that replaces this website. If the changes are significant, Librarika will provide a more prominent notice (including notice on web interface, for certain services, email notification or other means).

### 12\. Data Transfer

We use cloud servers located in various part of the world for backup and faster content delivery purposes (CDN) and your information may be processed on servers located outside of the country where you live. Data protection laws vary among countries, with some providing more protection than others. Regardless of where your information is processed, we apply the same protections described in this policy. 

### 13\. Contact Information

Librarika welcomes your feedback regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have questions, comments or concerns about this policy, please contact us by email at [info@raynux.com](mailto:info@raynux.com) or by mail through: 

Raynux, 373, Road 10, Block C, Bashundhara RA, Dhaka -1212 Bangladesh
